<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | Clemson Agribusiness Decision Research Lab</title>
    <link>https://cuagdecisionlab.github.io/news/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://cuagdecisionlab.github.io/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://cuagdecisionlab.github.io/media/icon_hu1295621753823738898.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>https://cuagdecisionlab.github.io/news/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Team</title>
      <link>https://cuagdecisionlab.github.io/news/join-the-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://cuagdecisionlab.github.io/news/join-the-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are always welcome brilliant and young mind join our lab and gain hands-on experience in applied economic research in agribusiness decision.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Graduate Students&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have available MS assistantship positions at our lab. Typically, the graduate students who receive assistantship in our lab need to be enrolled as a full time MS student in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clemson.edu/cafls/academics/graduate/agricultural-and-applied-economics.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Agricultural nd Applied Economics program&lt;/a&gt; at Clemson University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As members of our lab, you will collaborate closely with our faculty and graduate students on various studies focusing on agribusiness decision-making. You will gain knowledge on applied economic research method, data science, and decision sciences. From time to time, we will also collaborate across multi-displinary research groups to conduct research. We will provide both formal and informal training through group and individual meetings, conference and workshop attendance, and interactions with others in the lab and department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please email a &lt;em&gt;CV&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;a brief description of experience and career goals&lt;/em&gt; to Dr. Yefan Nian (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ynian@clemson.edu&#34;&gt;ynian@clemson.edu&lt;/a&gt;) or Dr. Michael Vassalos (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mvassal@clemson.edu&#34;&gt;mvassal@clemson.edu&lt;/a&gt;). For full admission details, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clemson.edu/cafls/academics/graduate/agricultural-and-applied-economics.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Online Graduate Application&lt;/a&gt;. Please indicate your interest in working with Dr. Yefan Nian or Dr. Michael Vassalos in your application.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;h2&gt; Undergraduate Students&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wlcome undegraudate students join our lab as a research assistant and gain hands on experience on conducting applied economic research related to decision-making in agribusiness. As a research assistant, you will collaborate closely with our faculty and graduate students on various projects. Your responsibilities could include participant recruitment, experimental preparation, data collection and analysis, and literature reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To apply, please email a &lt;em&gt;CV&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;a brief description of experience and career goals&lt;/em&gt; to Dr. Yefan Nian (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ynian@clemson.edu&#34;&gt;ynian@clemson.edu&lt;/a&gt;) or Dr. Michael Vassalos (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mvassal@clemson.edu&#34;&gt;mvassal@clemson.edu&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
